3rd Girls' Fighter Wing
Feeling a bit nervous, Miyamori?
（渡辺(わたなべ)）
もしかして宮森(みやもり) 緊張してる？
（あおい）
はい！
I am!
（渡辺）気楽にいこうよ
（稲浪(いななみ)）そうそう
Just relax.
That's right.
I'm sorry we couldn't get
episode 1 colored for recording.
あの １話 色つかなくて
すみませんでした
Yeah, I was hoping at least this first episode would be done on time.
ああ １話くらいはオールカラーに
してほしかったけどね
I'm really sorry.
ホント 申し訳ありません
Don't be so mean to our ace, Inanami-san.
うちのエースを
いじめないでくださいよ
稲浪さん
I hear you've been bullying all the new kids recently.
最近 若い子に厳しいって
評判だよ～
Who, me?
やめてよ
My New Year's resolution is to be the nicest sound engineer ever.
僕は今年から音響で一番
優しい人になるって決めたんだから
You say that every year.
（渡辺）
毎年言ってるじゃないっすか
Suzuki Kyouko
Aria's VA
Good morning.
（伊藤(いとう)）
おはようございま～す
Good morning!
（鈴木(すずき)）
おはようございます
ありあ役の鈴木京子(きょうこ)です！
I'm Suzuki Kyouko, playing Aria.
I look forward to working with you.
本日は
よろしくお願いいたします！
Likewise.
（伊藤）
よろしくお願いしま～す
Suzuki-san, don't sit on the end like that.
（ベテラン声優）鈴木さん
（鈴木）はい！
Yes!
そんな端っこに座ってちゃダメだよ
ほら 真ん中に
Come sit in the middle.
But I'm still a beginner.
（鈴木）いえ 私は新人ですので
（ベテラン声優）いやいや
Beginner or not, the main character's voice gets the middle seat.
主役ってのは新人だろうと
真ん中に座るもんだ
Okay.
はい！
Orii Yui
Suzuki Kyouko's Manager
I'm from the association.
I leave Suzuki in your capable hands.
（織居）
俳連です
本日は鈴木を
よろしくお願いいたします
Yeah, we'll do our best.
はい よろしくね
The actors have all arrived.
（中田）
役者さん そろいました
挨拶お願いしま～す
Come in and greet them.
Okay.
はい
Katsuragi-san, director, and...
葛城(かつらぎ)さん 監督と あれ？
原作者サイドは誰か
Is anyone representing the author here?
Nogame isn't coming.
His editor, Chazawa-san, has yet to arrive.
（葛城）
ああ 野亀(のがめ)先生は来ません
編集の茶沢(ちゃざわ)さんも まだですね
Watanabe-san, too.
（稲浪）あと渡辺さん
（渡辺）宮森
Miyamori, go in my stead.
（渡辺）俺の代わりに行け
（あおい）えっ？
（稲浪）行くぞエース！
（あおい）ああ はい！
Let's get going, ace.
R-Roger!
（稲浪）
え～ 本日から収録の
「第三飛行少女隊」
We'll be recording the voices for
3rd Girls' Fighter Wing starting today.
Let me introduce some key members of the staff.
その関係者さんからのですね
ご挨拶ということで
まず ウエスタン
エンタテイメントの葛城さん
First, Katsuragi-san from Western Entertainment.
えっと 葛城です
Hello, I'm Katsuragi.
「サンジョ」は夜鷹(よたか)書房さんの
人気原作です
3rd Wing is a hit series from Nighthawk Publishing.
Um... Ah, right...
え～っと ああそうだ
It's getting animated by Musashino Animation, a studio on a hot streak.
あの それをアニメ化するのが
今 ノリに乗ってる―
武蔵野(むさしの)アニメーションさん
ということで
How should I put it...
えっと こう
なんていうかですね あの
Please help us make 3rd Wing a great success!
ぜひぜひ キャストの皆さんの力で
「サンジョ」を大ヒット作に
飛び立たせてください
Let's set sights on drawing top ratings and take off!
そう　あの空にテークオフです！
That's all. I look forward to working with you.
ということで
よろしくお願いします
（一同）
よろしくお願いしま～す
Thanks for having us!
次 監督の木下(きのした)さんです
Next, Director Kinoshita.
（木下）
ああ 木下です
I'm Kinoshita.
S-So 3rd Wing is... Well...
Do you have any questions?
えっと「サンジョ」はですね
う～ん… あの
何か質問ありますか？
（鈴木）
はい！　ありあ役の鈴木です
Yes! I'm Suzuki, playing Aria.
What's Aria's...
あの ありあの…
Aria's...?
ありあの？
What's her blood type?
血液型は何型でしょうか？
Her... blood type?
（木下）血液型…
（鈴木）はい
Yes.
Sorry, I don't know.
すみません　分かりません
I see. I'm sorry.
そうですか
申し訳ありませんでした
That's all.
あの 以上です　次はデスクの…
Next, the PM—
Wait, director, is that really it?
（あおい）
えっ ちょっと
それだけですか？　監督
I forgot what I was going to say.
だって 話すこと忘れちゃった
はあ～ “ウィンウィン”ですよ！
Win-win! Remember?
（あおい）ほら！
（木下）あっ そうです！
That's right!
The theme of this project is "win-win"!
この作品のテーマは
“ウィンウィン”です！
I want to make sure everyone involved is happy!
関わったみんなが
幸せになれる作品を目指してます！
The lead role in this project belongs to you, the cast!
そして作品の主役は
あなた方 キャストの皆さんです！
You really do say that to everyone.
全セクションに言ってますね　それ
Shh! They can hear you!
シーッ 聞こえるでしょ！
しっかり聞こえましたよ　監督
You bet we can, director.
Cut me some slack, Itou-san.
うわ… キツいな　伊藤さん
（笑い声）
（稲浪）改めて宮森さん
Now let's hear from Miyamori-san.
I'm the production manager, Miyamori Aoi.
制作デスクの宮森あおいです
「サンジョ」は
As for 3rd Wing, the director and all the other staff are very excited about it.
監督 スタッフも最高に乗っていて
I honestly believe that everyone involved will lead this project.
本当に関わっている
誰もが主役だと心から思っています
Though it's only a one-cour show, I will make sure I'm working just as hard as everyone here!
１(ワン)クールという短い間ですが
キャストさんたちに負けないように
頑張りたいと思いますので
Thanks for your cooperation!
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you too.
（一同）
よろしくお願いします
Good one. I liked the atmosphere you created.
お疲れ　いい雰囲気だったよ
Well done, Ace-kun!
エース君 グッジョブだよ
Me? Really?
（あおい）私ですか？
（木下）えっ 俺は？
What about me?
No dice.
（稲浪）ダメでしょ
（中田）では テストいきま～す
Let's start with the test.
You Set Me Up Well!
Thank you!
（一同）
お疲れさまでした～
Next week, we'll do interviews after recording.
（中田）
次週は収録後 取材入りま～す
Huh?
（茶沢）
あ～れれ
Funny thing is, it looks like the recording session is over.
あの変な話 収録終わってます？
No, Aria's actress has to stay a little longer.
いや ありあの子が
居残りになってます
あら～
Oh.
I'm terribly sorry about the trouble Suzuki caused.
（織居）
この度は鈴木がご迷惑をおかけして
申し訳ありません
It's fine.
（稲浪）
いえいえ よくあることなので
ご心配なく
Happens all the time. Don't worry.
I'm very sorry.
（織居）
ホントにすみません
SMOKING ROOM
Her voice is different from the auditions.
（木下）
オーディションの時と
全然 声が違っちゃってるね
So... timid.
（稲浪）
なんか こびた声なんだよな
Maybe she heard you're harsh on young ladies and is feeling nervous?
稲浪さんが若い子に厳しいって
ウワサ聞いて 萎縮してるとか
I told you I'm Mr. Nice Guy now.
だから僕は
一番優しい人になったって…
She's basically a beginner—
まあ ほぼ新人さんですし
'Scuse me! Funny thing is,
something came up so I'm leaving!
すいませ～ん
別件あるんで お先で～す
Goodbye!
（一同）
お疲れさまです
Miyamori, go talk to her.
宮森 ちょっと行ってきな
Um, is the recording starting?
あっ もう収録始まります？
Not yet. Here.
あっ いえ　あの これ
Thank you, Miyamori-san!
ありがとうございます　宮森さん
Y-You remembered my name?
お… 覚えてくれてたんですね！
Of course!
（鈴木）
もちろんです！
I memorized all the names in the staff list.
台本のスタッフ欄に並んでる方は
全員覚えてます
This is the only show I'm working on, so...
私 他に作品持ってないですから
3rd Girls' Fighter Wing
Episode 1
Aria, we're starting!
（稲浪）
ありあ 始めるよ～
Okay!
はい！
You can do it!
（あおい）頑張ってください！
（鈴木）頑張ります！
Thank you!
Aria
Because I'm like ice.
氷みたいだから　心なんて もう
Cathy
I've already thrown my heart away!
捨てちゃったから！
（稲浪）
はい お待ちくださ～い
One moment, please.
Just a little more.
（葛城）
もう少しなんですけどね
If she could sound a bit more natural...
あとちょっと自然な感じがね
I've already...
Aria
Cathy, reacting to Aria's answer
The sun beautifully sinking
into the sea of clouds
Aria's expression doesn't change
Aria barely reacts to Cathy's words
Cathy smiles gently
Aria's eyes open wide in surprise
Tears gush out
"Ice doll"
Aria             "Because I'm like ice."
Cathy             "?"
Aria                "I've already thrown my heart away!"
Cathy           "No way."
Aria                "..."
Cathy            "But you cried all the time while fighting."
Aria                  "!!"
Cathy             "You kept cried, mumbling how hard, how painful it was."
（鈴木）
“心なんて”
I've already thrown my heart away!
心なんて もう捨てちゃったから！
Aria, did you stop anywhere on the way to the recording?
（稲浪）
ありあ 今日はスタジオ来る前
どこか寄った？
Yes, I bought water at a convenience store after I got off the train.
はい
駅降りた後
コンビニでお水買ってきました
Inside the station?
構内のコンビニ？
No, the one next to the beef bowl place nearby.
いえ この近くの牛丼屋のそばの
All you got was water?
水買っただけ？
Yes, that was it.
えっと はい　今日はそうです
What about the bottle?
ペットボトルは？
I've already thrown it away.
もう捨てちゃいました
Say it again.
はい もう一度
あっ… もう捨てちゃいました
I've already thrown it away.
Keep the tone, but make it "thrown my heart away."
（稲浪）
うん　じゃあその感じで
“捨てちゃったから”
えっ？　捨てちゃったから！
Thrown my heart away!
また力入った　さっきのままで
Sounds too tense again.
Say it like you did earlier.
I've already thrown my heart away.
心なんて もう―
捨てちゃったから
（葛城）おお～！
We're rolling.
（藤）
回りました
Say, Lt. Catherine—
あの キャサリン少尉
Cathy!
（伊藤）キャシー
（鈴木）キャシー
Cathy.
Is it true that none of your memories have returned?
（鈴木）
本当に記憶 戻ってないの？
The B1B believed to be carrying a pillar's seed is approaching, escorted by a fighter squadron.
（ヴァロア役）
ピラーのシードを
搭載したと思われるＢ１Ｂが
戦闘機に護衛され接近中です
You must stop it at all costs.
なんとしても阻止してください
Let's go, girls!
（クリスティーネ役）
行くわよ みんな！
Roger!
はい！
We got it.
（稲浪）いただきました
（鈴木）ハッ！
Ending
Thank you very much!
ありがとうございました！
Keep it up for next week too!
（稲浪）
よ～し 来週もこの感じで
頑張って
Okay!
はい！
Not you.
お前じゃねえよ
Has Ookura-san returned?
あの 大倉(おおくら)さんは
お戻りになりました？
（美術マン）
社長 結局
打ち合わせから戻らなくて
He never came back after his meeting.
I'm so sorry. You call every day.
ごめんなさいね　毎日かけてるのに
It's okay.
（あおい）
いえ
You know, he might be...
（美術マン）
そうだ　もしかしたらだけど
Bird Park?
“バードパーク”　そんなスタジオ
I've never...
heard of that studio...
どこにもない
There it is.
あった
Skewer BBQ
Bird Park
（引き戸の開閉音）
（あおい）すみません　失礼します
Excuse me!
Is there someone named Ookura here?
あの 大倉さんという方は
いらっしゃいますか？
Um, Ookura-san?
あの 大倉さん？
Ookura-san!
大倉さん
Huh? Who're you?
Ookura Masahiro
Ookura Workshop    President
お前 誰？
はじめまして
I'm Miyamori Aoi from Musashino Animation. Nice to meet you.
武蔵野アニメーションの
宮森と申します
Musani, huh?
ムサニか　まだあったんだ
They're still alive and kicking?
I'm here because I have a request for you.
本日はお願いがあって伺いました
What are you having, missus?
（おかみ）
お姉さん ご注文は？
えっ ああ
ウーロン茶 お願いします
O-Oolong tea, please.
What?! Not booze?!
はあ？　お酒じゃないの？
Sorry, I'm driving.
（あおい）車ですので
（大倉）チッ！
I'm so lonely!
あ～ 俺は孤独だ！
Aoi-chan, how old do you think I am?
あおいちゃん おじさん
いくつだと思う？
I don't know.
いえ 分かりません
Well, if you had to guess, what'd it be?
いくちゅだと思うかって
聞いてるの～
う～ん… 50くらいですか？
Around 50?
So close! I'm 60!
惜しい～ 60歳！
お若いですね！
You're so young!
Young? You sure know how to make an old man happy!
おお！　若いってさ
おじさん うれしいな～！
お世辞に決まってるでしょ
She's just being polite.
え～ そんなことないよね？
She meant it! Right?
あの 私は大倉さんに
お仕事をお願いしたくてですね
I'm here because I have a job request for you.
It's a series airing this fall,
titled 3rd Girls' Fighter Wing.
今年の秋 放映予定の
「第三飛行少女隊」という
シリーズなんですが
Backgrounds are all done digitally nowadays.
背景もデジタルの時代に
紙と絵の具使ってる俺に
What would you have me,
a paper-and-paint man, even do?
今更 何描けっていうのよ
I'm not taking art direction jobs either,
もう美監だってやってないし
and people just treat me like an annoying old fart.
どうせうるさいだけの
じじい扱いだよ
Yeah, yeah. I know they hate me because I have a short fuse.
分かってんのよ　怒りっぽいから
嫌われてるってえのは
If you know, why not do something about it?
（おかみ）
分かってるなら直せば？
If only I could!
でも 直せないんだよな～
You understand, right, Aoi-chan?
分かる？　あおいちゃん
There's a scene I'd like to ask you to do.
あの 今回大倉さんに背景を
お願いしたいシーンがあるんです
You'd like to ask me, huh?
お願いしたいねえ
Do you even know what I've worked on before?
大体 俺が
何やってた人間か知ってんの？
Of course! Local Space Force, right?
もちろんです！
「町立宇宙軍」ですよね？
違うな　やってない！
Nope, that wasn't me.
えっ えっと ああ…
大変失礼いたしました！
I'm terribly sorry!
Just kidding!
ウソだよ～ん！
Our director really would love you to work on this.
うちの監督が
ぜひ大倉さんにお願いしたいと
言っておりまして
His name is Kinoshita.
木下っていうんですが…
All righty then, I'll do it.
（大倉）
はいはい やりますやります
I'm totally doing it!
（あおい）えっ？
（大倉）やりますよ～！
Really? Thank you very much!
本当ですか？
ありがとうございます！
I'll come with the art director at 17:00 tomorrow to discuss the details.
あの それじゃあ あした17時に
美監さんと説明に伺いますので
Sure thing. Gotcha.
（大倉）
はいはい 喜んで
As for what I'll need to bring...
それで お持ちするもの
なんですけど…
（いびき）
あれっ あの 大倉さん？
Uh, Ookura-san?
He'll be like that for a while.
（おかみ）当分 起きないわよ
（あおい）えっ？
Huh?
It's okay. Just leave him be.
大丈夫よ　ほっときなさい
Hiraoka-kun's not here today either.
（丸川(まるかわ)）
今日も平岡(ひらおか)君 来てないの？
His email said he had to stop elsewhere first.
（興津(おきつ)）
メールでは立ち寄りになってました
Miyamori-san, any idea where he might be?
宮森さん どこか把握してる？
No. I'll ask him when he comes.
いえ 来たら確認します
（丸川）
う～ん… そういや宮森さん
Oh right, Miyamori-san!
Nabe-chan told me Ookura-kun accepted the job.
ナベちゃんから聞いたけど
大倉君が仕事受けてくれたって？
The Ookura-san?
（興津）あの大倉さんが？
（あおい）はい！
Yes.
3 p.m. and there's still no one there?
まさか３時でも誰もいないのか
That's quite something, Taitanic.
（安藤(あんどう)）
さすがですね タイタニックさん
And they call themselves working adults?
（佐藤(さとう)）
それ社会人として
ありえるんですか？
Their production team is understaffed, so that's just how they are.
（平岡）
あそこ 制作の人数少ないから
しかたないよ
Who cares as long as they get stuff done?
まっ 帳尻さえ合えば
いいんじゃない
Hiraoka-kun, make sure you
always tell us where you are.
平岡君 立ち寄り先は
毎回必ず報告するように
Got it.
はいは～い
（舌打ち）
帳尻さえ合えばいいだろ
Who cares as long as I get stuff done?
あっ！　久乃木(くのぎ)さん
Kunogi-san?
You want me to check your keyframes?
（絵麻）ああ 原画見てほしいの？
（久乃木）うう…
Tatiana
You've improved!
（絵麻）
よくなったんじゃない
動きもちゃんとしてるし
Tatiana
The movement looks fine to me.
These look ready to turn in.
一度 これで出してみようか
Ret—
もど…
Of course, it might be returned,
but I've had that happen all the time too.
（絵麻）
戻ってくるかもしれないけど
私だって いつもそうだったよ
You improve by doing retakes and fixing your mistakes over and over again.
リテークで戻されて直すの
繰り返しで うまくなるんだし
Dir!
（久乃木）かん…
（絵麻）監督
The director?
Command
room
Valois peeking out between
the blinds
Man
"(inaudible)"
Stern expression. Hand out
(SE) piin    Valois
"Then I can send
them on a sortie as usual?"
Long
Understood.
Man looking
through binoculars
van stopped on
the runway
Valois
"At the
destination. Yes."
Command
room
Valois peeking out between
the blinds
Man
"(inaudible)"
Stern expression. Hand out
(SE) piin    Valois
"Then I can send
them on a sortie as usual?"
Long
Understood.
Command
room
Valois peeking out between
the blinds
Man
"(inaudible)"
Stern expression. Hand out
(SE) piin    Valois
"Then I can send
them on a sortie as usual?"
Long
Understood.
Command
room
Valois peeking out between
the blinds
Man
"(inaudible)"
Stern expression. Hand out
(SE) piin    Valois
"Then I can send
them on a sortie as usual?"
Long
Understood.
Board!
Command
room
Valois peeking out between
the blinds
Man
"(inaudible)"
Stern expression. Hand out
(SE) piin    Valois
"Then I can send
them on a sortie as usual?"
Long
Understood.
（久乃木）こん…
（絵麻）監督の絵コンテ？
Command
room
Valois peeking out between
the blinds
Man
"(inaudible)"
Stern expression. Hand out
(SE) piin    Valois
"Then I can send
them on a sortie as usual?"
Long
Understood.
The director's storyboards?
He started in production, so his drawings—
確かに制作出身だから
絵はあれだけど
That's not it?
（絵麻）違うの？
（久乃木）ちが… おと
Handwrit! Li! Bro!
Li... Little brother?
（絵麻）おと… 弟
（久乃木）うっ！
Resem!
にて！
Ah! His handwriting resembles your little brother's?
ああ 字が弟さんに似てるんだね
Stern expression. Hand out
(SE) piin  Valois
"Then I can send
on a sortie as usual?"
Sorry! Just noticed you gave us a call!
（三村(みむら)）
すいませ～ん
電話もらってたっぽくて
It's about 3rd Wing.
（あおい）
「サンジョ」の５話ですが
We haven't gotten any layouts from you yet.
What's the status on those?
まだレイアウト上がりが
一つも来てないんで
進捗状況を確認させてください
Uh... Let's see...
（三村）
あ～ えっと～
Looks like it's over half done.
Schedule
Tanaka works
at home
あ～ もう半分以上
上がってるみたいですね
Then why haven't we received anything?
（あおい）
えっ それじゃあ
なんでこちらには…
All the cuts are stalled at the ED.
（三村）
いや～ まだ演出さんで
全カット止まってて
He's really busy, so he only comes here two nights each week.
超忙しい人なんで
うちには週２で夜しか入れてなくて
Mimura Kenichi
Studio Taitanic    Production Manager
I have to organize the director's checks too, so I'd like to start getting them tomorrow.
こちらの監督チェックの
段取りもありますので
あしたから
出していただきたいんですが
I'll ask, but I can't make any promises.
（三村）
まあ 聞いてはみますけど
どうかな～
Thanks.
お願いします
（通話が切れた音）
Miyamori-san, what about Ookura-kun?
宮森さん 大倉君とこは？
I'm leaving now.
（あおい）今 出るとこです
（丸川）よかった～
Great. Take this along.
これ お土産
Tell him I'm glad we can work together.
大倉君に言ってね
“どうぞ よろしくお願いします”
って
Ookura
Workshop
Are you nervous, Atsumi-san?
（あおい）
渥美(あつみ)さん 緊張してます？
（渥美）
そりゃもう 大倉さんって
Of course. Ookura-san is the reason I entered this field.
私が この世界に入った
きっかけの人ですから
Oh, really?
えっ そうなんですか？
The scene in Local Space Force with the dead city was amazing!
「町立宇宙軍」の
死に絶えた町のシーン 最高でした
（大倉）
うう… 頭痛(いて)え
Man, my head...
Hello! Miyamori here, checking back with you.
おはようございます　宮森です
This is the art director for 3rd Wing, Atsumi-san.
こちら「サンジョ」の
美術監督の渥美さんです
I'm Atsumi Yuuji. Thank you very much for agreeing to assist us.
渥美裕治(ゆうじ)です　この度は
お手伝いいただけるとのことで
ありがとうございます！
（渥美）うん？
（あおい）あの…
Um...
Who are you?
きみら 誰？
Ookura-san! I'm Miyamori from Musani!
I met you at the skewer chicken joint last night!
大倉さん ゆうべ焼き鳥屋さんで
ご挨拶した ムサニの宮森です
いや 知らない
Doesn't ring a bell.
We talked! You accepted the job too!
お話ししましたよ！
仕事も受けて
くださったじゃないですか
Like I said, I've never even seen you before.
だから そもそも会ってねえし
You have! I gave you my card too.
お会いしてます
名刺も渡しました
I think you put it in your wallet.
あっ 確か
お財布に入れてましたよ
Never got anything like that.
だから もらってねえって
名刺なんて
I'd remember something like that,
even if I was drunk out of my you-know-what.
俺はな どんなに酔ってたって
そんくらいのことは覚えてんだよ
Musashino Animation
Production Manager
180-0024
Tokyo, Musashino, Sakai-kita 2-2-11
Musashino Animation Inc.
TEL 03-6908-8821
E-mail miyamori@musani.jp
Ah, Aoi-chan! I remember now!
あおいちゃんだ 思い出したよ！
ハハハ…
My bad!
悪い 悪い
で… すまんが
昨日のことは忘れてくれ
Anyway, forget what I said yesterday.
I'm not taking the job.
（大倉）仕事は受けない
（渥美）そんな！
But...
There a problem?
何？
No. I'm sorry.
いえ 申し訳ありません
You're Atsumi? The kid who worked under Aoyama?
お前 渥美だっけ
青山(あおやま)んとこの弟子か？
Yes.
はい
Don't believe a word of anything he's said about me.
あいつが俺について
なんか言ってたら全部ウソだから
Especially about the time with Sagamori-san. It's all lies.
特に佐賀森(さがもり)さんとこに
いた頃の話は
何もかもウソっぱちだからな
Okay.
As for 3rd Girls' Fighter Wing...
あの「第三飛行少女隊」の
お話なんですけど…
Drop it.
その話は終わり
俺はやんない　以上！
I'm not doing it and that's that.
We asked Atsumi-san to focus on the airiness of the skies and the texture of the clouds.
今回のアニメ化にあたって
美術の空気感
空の雲の質感にこだわりたいと
渥美さんにお願いしまして
The clouds are done with CG anyway, aren't they?
どうせ雲は３Ｄなんだろ？
That's right.
はい　そこと整合性のある空は
私の仕事です
I'm in charge of making the sky mesh well with that.
We would like to ask you to do another, fairly important scene—
今回お願いしたいのは
まったく独立した―
特に大事なシーンでして
そんな大事なシーンを
こんなおっさんに投げるなんて
Why would you throw such an important scene at me?
If I were you, I'd rather die than ask a guy like me.
俺だったら死んでもイヤだけどな
Why aren't you doing it yourself?
なんで自分でやんねえの？
Well...
いや それは…
See? You want to do it yourself. Do it then.
ほら やりてえんだろ？
やりなよ
It's true that if I could, I'd want to do them all myself.
確かに自分で全部
やれるならやりたいです
I have pride too.
私にもプライドがあります
See?
（大倉）だろ？
（渥美）でも 今は
But right now, I'm focused on making the skies and clouds perfect for the planes to soar through.
飛行機が飛ぶ空と雲を
最高にすることで頭がいっぱいで
When I heard there's a scene with a ruined city, I remembered your dead city from Space Force!
廃虚の話を聞いた時
思いついたのは
大倉さんの描かれた―
「町立」の死に絶えた町の
イメージなんです
But I can't paint anything even close to that.
でも あれに追いつく絵なんて
私にはとても
冗談だろ？
You've gotta be kidding me.
You're asking a ruined man to draw a ruined city?
それこそ俺自身が
廃虚みたいなもんだっての
Just kidding.
なんつって
Please. Let me learn from you.
お願いします　勉強させてください
All the more reason to do it yourself.
それなら なおさら自分でやりな
そこ超えてみせろ
Go ahead and surpass me.
Don't count on an old fart like me.
俺みたいなロートルに頼るな
Now then, shall we get to drinking?
さてと そろそろ飲みに行くか
Wanna come along, Atsumi?
（大倉）渥美 一緒に行くか？
（あおい）あっ そうだ
Oh right. I've got a little something for you.
これ つまらない物ですが
What, booze?
何 お酒？
おっ こりゃまさか！
No way!
Cathouse
うお～！
こねこやのどら焼き！
Dorayaki from the Cathouse!
This brings back memories!
懐かしいな～！
う～ん！　これ
Man! The way the red bean filling just melts...
この一瞬で溶けちゃうみたいな
あんこがもう…
How did you know I loved these?
でも なんで俺が
これ好きなの知ってたの？
Marukawa asked me to give these to you.
あの うちの丸川が大倉さんにって
Marukawa? Who's that?
（大倉）丸川って誰？
（あおい）うちの社長です
Musani's president.
Marukawa-san is back at Musani?
丸川さん ムサニに戻ってたの…
You conniving little... You set me up!
お前ら汚(きたね)えぞ！
俺をハメやがったな！
You get me to take a bite before saying it's from Marukawa-san!
先に食わせてから
丸川さんの名前出すとか！
That's not fair! Warn me beforehand!
ずりいじゃねえか！
最初っから言えよ！
You opened the box and started eating on your own.
いきなり食べたの
大倉さんじゃないですか
Also...
（あおい）それから
（大倉）まだ あんのか
What else?
Marukawa wanted me to tell you
丸川が言っておりました
that he's glad you can work together.
“どうぞ よろしくお願いします”
って
そう… 丸川さんが
Marukawa-san said that?
That he's glad we can work together?
“どうぞ よろしく”って
Yes.
With me?
俺に 言ってた…
Yes.
（あおい）はい
（大倉）まったく―
Geez, I can't let my guard down for even a second.
油断も隙もありゃしねえ
Only the ruined city scene, got it?
廃虚のシーンだけだぞ
Of course!
（渥美）はい！
（あおい）ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
You are aware that I work on paper, right?
分かってんだろうけど
俺は紙だからな
And I won't let you alter my stuff afterwards.
それにあとからドカドカ
手加えたら 許さねえからな
はい　もちろんです！
Yes, of course.
でさあ 美術ボードなしの
1発背景でもいいかな？
Can I go ahead and do backgrounds, without concept art?
え？　はい 結構です
Yes.
Thank you so much!
（あおい･渥美）
よろしくお願いします！
Look at that! That's like 200 cuts!
（太郎(たろう)）
どうよこれ
200カットは余裕であんじゃね
The ED at Taitanic put out all the cuts he had stalled!
タイタニックの演出さん
たまってたレイアウト
全部出してくれました
Director, you can go over all this today, right?
監督 チェック
今日いっぱいで大丈夫ですよね？
No way! No way! No way!
無理 無理 無理 無理！
３日 いやせめて２日は…
Give me three... at least two days!
Okay, then tomorrow night's the deadline!
はい　あしたいっぱいで
お願いします！
宮森～
Miyamori!
（太郎）
コンビニの弁当は
基本11時に届くんだけど
The packed meals arrive at the store at 11:00,
Meat Mix Pack Lunch
店員が並べるの遅いと
but if the clerks are slow, it'll take until about 11:30 before they're all out.
11時半 過ぎないと
全部出ないんだよね
The safest and best bet is the fifteen-minute window between 11:45 and 12:00.
万全を期すなら45分過ぎから
12時までの15分が勝負
This is important.
これ重要だから
Right.
（佐藤）はあ…
（太郎）あとは さかいていね
And for Sakaitei,
Fresh Packed Meals
Sakaitei
I recommend their fried chicken meal.
ここは なんといっても
からあげ弁当がおすすめ
Director Kinoshita loves it too.
木下監督のお墨付き
There's also a mixed cutlet pack, and if you want something simple, a nori meal...
それ以外だとミックスカツ弁や
初心に返って のり弁も…
Hey, Miyamori! What's up with these layouts?!
（木下）
ちょっと宮森！
（木下）何このレイアウト！
（あおい）はい！
Yes?
Look here, at Catherine!
（木下）
ほら ここのキャサリン
I said to draw her in street clothes,
but here she's in uniform!
打ち合わせで私服にするって
言ったのに 制服のまま！
Her pose is different in the next cut too!
しかも次のカット
ポーズが違ってる！
But this takes the cake!
Sky
極めつきはこれ！
The storyboards have Aria, but the layout has Tatiana!
コンテでは ありあなのに
レイアウトはタチアナ！
Sky
Did they just ignore all the notices and messages?
（円(まどか)）
伝達事項や お約束を
すっ飛ばしちゃったんですかね
They didn't do even the most basic work.
（山田(やまだ)）
最低限の作業もやってませんね
No way the ED looked at this.
これ絶対 演出が見てない！
But the ED check field is signed!
3rd Girls'
Fighter Wing
ED
Director
Effects
（あおい）
でも演出欄にサイン入ってます
Impossible! This isn't checked!
これで演出チェック済みとか
ありえない！
What if the Taitanic PA signed it just to get it out?
もしかしてタイタニックの制作が
勝手にチェック済みにして
出したとか
Do people actually do that?
（あおい）
あるんですか？　そんなこと
We'd never deliver work that hasn't been checked.
Schedule
いや 勝手に出すなんて
ありえないですよ
Can you contact the ED?
演出さんに連絡取れませんか？
Now?
（三村）
今からですか？
Here, her poses are all different,
Yakushiji Zaruyoshi
Episode Director
（木下）
ほら こことここ
ポーズがバラバラで
and here this is the wrong character.
そもそもキャラが違う
I'll admit it. I made a mistake.
（薬師寺）
それはこっちのミスです
認めます
But I have five shows on my hands.
Can't be a perfectionist.
ただこっちも５本
掛け持ちしてますし
完璧ってわけにはですね…
This isn't about perfection.
いや“完璧”とかじゃなくて
ほら このセリフシート
Did you even look at this speech sheet?
（木下）ちゃんと見てます？
（薬師寺）見てますよ
I did.
It's the climax of a very tense scene!
だってこれ 緊迫したシーンの
“敵機だ！”ってセリフですよ
Yet you're using four seconds? E-ne-my?!
E
NE
MY
なのに４秒も使ってる！
“て～っきだ～！”
それでいいと判断したんで
I decided that was the best.
Anyway, I'd like you to look over these a bit more carefully.
とにかく もう少し丁寧に
見てもらえますか？
Fine.
分かりました
もう一度 考えてみます
I'll give them another look.
That's great. Thanks.
ありがとう　助かります
Kinoshita-san.
（薬師寺）木下さん
（木下）えっ
I concede this time,
今回はいったん引きますけどね
but if you keep being such a perfectionist on TV shows, you'll get burned again.
でもテレビに見あわないこと
ばっかやってると―
また事故りますよ
（木下）あっ
Director?
（あおい）監督！
（木下）くう～！
I'm so pissed, I don't know what to say back!
言い返せないけど悔しい～！
Huh? A break?
Ookura Workshop
Connected
（あおい）
えっ お休み？
Yes. He said he won't be back for two weeks.
（美術マン）
はい ２週間くらい帰らないと…
I had just assumed he refused your job request.
あれっ てっきりムサニさんの
お仕事断ったんだとばかり…
No way! Do you know where he is?
そんな！　行き先は分かりますか？
（美術マン）
あ… いえ まったく
No idea.
Do you have his cell phone number?
携帯をお教え願えますか？
The number you have called is currently unavailable...
（留守電音声）
おかけになった電話は…
Miyamori-san, are you okay?
宮森さん 大丈夫ですか？
He ran away. When it came down to getting stuff done, he got fed up.
逃げたな～ いざとなったら
面倒くさくなったんだよ
I know the feeling.
俺にはよ～く分かる
Huh? The ED quit?!
（あおい）
はあ 演出さんが降りた？
（三村）
ええ うち戻ってから
Yeah.
When we got back, he suddenly said he couldn't handle 3rd Wing.
「サンジョ」は無理なんで
辞めますって いきなり…
I knew he was busy, but this...
Schedule
忙しいっぽいのは
知ってたんですがね～
Can you find someone to replace him?
じゃあ 代わりの演出さんは？
Can't think of anyone that could do it on such short notice.
（三村）
今いきなりは―
誰もいませんね～
Worst case, I could do it.
最悪は まあ俺が
えっ 三村さん
演出さんだったんですか？
Mimura-san, you have directing experience?
No, I'm production.
（三村）
いや 制作っすよ
But I figured it's better than nothing!
でも なんとなくだったら
俺でもやれるかなって
I have to consult my superiors about this first.
あの 私だけでは
判断できませんので
上と相談してみます
後ほど連絡します！
I'll call you later.
（三村）
は～い…
Okay—
Anything wrong?
あっ どうかした？
あの 渥美さんから大倉さんに
渡しそびれた物があるんで
Atsumi-san said he forgot to pass some materials to Ookura-san.
Please call him.
折り返し連絡くださいって
さっき井口(いぐち)さんが来て
Iguchi-san was asking about the AD schedule for episode 5.
５話の作監スケジュールを
教えてほしいって
I accidentally gave filming the wrong date for dubbing,
１話の
ダビング前差し替えの日付
間違えて伝えちゃったみたいで
撮影がとれねえって
怒りだしちゃって
and now they're saying they can't get it done.
どうしたらいいと思う？　宮森
What should I do, Miyamori?
Panic! Panic! What should she do now?
（ロロ）
パニック パニック どうすんの？
So many things at once! Of course she doesn't know!
（ミムジー）
いきなり いろんなこと
同時に言われても
分かんないよ！
But this is part of the PM's job.
でもでも それがデスクって
やつなのでは？
That doesn't make it any less impossible!
そんなこと言ったって
無理なものは無理！
Even if it's impossible to do it all at once,
全部を一度には無理でもね
if you take it one step at a time,
you'll finish eventually.
小さなことからコツコツやれば
いつかは終わるよ
One step at a time.
小さなことからコツコツと…
分かりました　井口さんには
私から連絡しておきます
Okay.
I'll talk with Iguchi-san myself.
Andou-san, please retrieve Kisa-san's ups.
安藤さんは
木佐(きさ)さんとこの回収お願い
Satou-san, please call editing,
ask what time they'll start, and tell the ED.
佐藤さんは編集に連絡して
スタート時間を聞いて
演出に伝えておいて
Okay!
分かりました！
行ってきます！
Right away!
タロさん あの…
Tarou-san, tha—
はあ～ どうしよう
What do I do now?
Who could I ask to direct that episode?
私が頼めそうな演出さんって誰？
Madoka-san? Yamada-san?
円さん？　山田さん？
No! They need to focus on episodes 3 and 4.
ダメ　２人とも３話と４話に
集中してもらわないと！
The director...
監督は… 絶対無理だし
Not a chance.
Youga-san and Matsuizaki-san...
用賀(ようが)さんと松井崎(まついざき)さんは
They both refused when I asked them to help with 3rd Wing!
そもそも２人とも「サンジョ」
誘った時点で断られてるし
Is there anyone else? Anyone?
（あおい）他にない？　他に
（ロロ･ミムジー）ううん
I can't think of anyone!
ダメ 全然思いつかない！
私じゃ無理！
I can't do this myself! What should I do?!
どうしよう
I'm out of ide—
万策尽き…
（ドアが開く音）
I'm back.
（矢野(やの)）
ただいま
Untranslated Beer
This is Musashino Animation.
You got your hands on some new kind of flour?
I'll have to give it a try!
Next time on Shirobako: "Did You Catch Any?"
Did You Catch Any?
ぷは～！
（丸川）
はい 武蔵野アニメーションです
えっ 新種の小麦が手に入った？
じゃあ 麺打ってみないと
次回
「ＳＨＩＲＯＢＡＫＯ(シロバコ)」